Today, I'm very honored to
welcome Sayak Paul from Hugging
Face, who works a lot on
diffusion models, image
generation and so forth.
So it's day-to-day
includes contributing
to the diffusers,
diffusers library,
training and babysitting
diffusion models,
and working on applied ideas.
He's interested in
subject-driven generation,
preference alignment, and
evaluation of diffusion models.
And when he is not
working, he can
be found playing the guitar and
binge-watching ICML tutorials
and Suits.
So without further ado,
I'll hand it off to Sayak.
I guess I'm here to depart and
deviate from the usual theme
that's followed at CS25.
I guess not a lot about
visual modality, especially
the generative aspects of them.
So I guess I'm happy
in a way that I'm here
to depart and deviate
from that theme.
So yeah.
I wanted to start with
a couple of disclaimers.
And this talk is
definitely not going
to be an exhaustive overview
of all the possible methods.
So it might be the case that
I didn't cover your work which
you thought to be very seminal,
so I apologize in advance.
And then I'm not
going to cover what
is diffusion or
flow-matching in details,
but I'll give a very
quick overview just
to set the context and tone.
And then the architectures
I'll discuss today
will be fairly agnostic to
diffusion or flow-matching.
And since I work on image
and videos primarily,
I will take my
examples with images.
But just know that
these architectures
are fairly well-known
to generalize
to other continuous
modalities such as audios.
And then of course I'll share
my slide after the talk.
And here's how I want
to approach this talk.
This is the rough
overview of all the things
that I want to cover.
As I mentioned, I'll give
you a brief introduction
to diffusion models or
flow-matching as well.
And then I'll try
to set the context
by discussing the early
architectures for diffusion--
the early architectures for
image generation in this field.
And then we'll head
straight to DiTs, and as I
like to call, their friends.
And I'll conclude
with some thoughts.
And in those
thoughts I'll discuss
some of the promising
directions that have
become lately interested in.
And then I'm sure there will
be time for Q&A. So yeah.
I really wanted to fascinate
you with all the cool examples
in the text-to-image arena, but
I guess at this point in time,
we all know these examples.
Because I think these days
we are becoming more and more
interested in native multi-modal
generation, not just images.
But nonetheless, I just
wanted to start off
by giving you a
couple of examples
from the text-to-image arena.
My favorite is the last one--
tiny astronaut hatching
from an egg on the moon.
I think human imagination
really took off there.
But yeah.
You can see apart from DALL-E
3 all these are open models,
and the photorealism
aspects of these models
are quite impressive.
So yeah.
And then I want to also
give you an infographic
of how I like to think about
diffusion models in general.
So I like to think
about diffusion models
as the following.
So when you take a
random noise vector
and what happens as you denoise
it over a period of time,
so that it becomes a
photorealistic image.
And if you take a
look closely, you
will notice that it's an
iterative process unlike GANs.
GANs are one-shot in nature, but
diffusion models are iterative.
It's sequential in nature.
So in a way, we are essentially
denoising the random noise
that we had started off
with, until and unless we
are done with the kind of
image that we are looking for.
So just know that it's
iterative in nature.
That's the main takeaway
from this slide.
When you start conditioning the
denoising process with text,
for example, you can
condition in lots of ways.
But let's say, I think text
is one of the more liberating
conditions.
As you start conditioning the
denoising process with text,
you get abstract
creatures like this.
But yeah, you will start
feeling very liberated
with text-to-image
as I like to believe.
And then let's take a step back
and start developing a mental
model of what it takes to
have a fairly state-of-the-art
text-to-image model.
Let's say I want to
get from this text
prompt a cat looking like a
tiger, and from all the way
up to the image on the top.
What does it take?
What are the components
that we are looking for?
How should they be connected?
So I want to give you a
connected graph of how
the different components
should be connected
so that we can
backtrack them and start
developing more intuition.
So of course, when
you have text,
you need to have some
of embedding so that you
can work with those
embeddings, and we
have text encoders for them.
And state-of-the-art
diffusion models,
they usually rely on more
than one text encoders.
For example, Stable
Diffusion three,
it relies on three text
encoders-- not one, not two,
but three.
So you have your text
prompt, you pass it off
to text encoders, and you
then have the embeddings.
And as we saw in
the earlier slide,
we are starting off with
some random noise drawn
from a Gaussian distribution.
So we are starting with
some noisy latents,
and then you have
your text embeddings.
And then you have
some time step,
which you draw-- which you
do the math with a scheduler.
I'm going to come to the
scheduler component in a minute.
But you have your conditions
at this point in time.
You have your text embeddings,
you have your noisy latents,
and you have some time step.
And then you have your
core diffusion network,
and you pass all these inputs
to your core diffusion network.
And it's a sequential process.
You run the diffusion network
over a period of time,
as we saw in the earlier slide.
And then it's going to give
you some refined latent.
And then you give it
to some decoder model
and you have your image out.
Now, I would like to call out
two broad classes of diffusion
models.
This overview
resembles the pixels--
the latent space
diffusion models.
But there's another class
of diffusion models,
which is called the pixel
space diffusion model.
But the recent-- or the state
of the diffusion models, they
are all latent space-based,
because pixel space
is quite prohibitive and
computationally intensive
in nature.
That's why it's more common
to see latent space diffusion
models.
So that's why you see
noisy latents there
and not raw pixels.
And if you were
to generalize this
to other continuous
modalities, the basic idea
here is how do you represent
the raw modality data points,
and how do you compute
intermediate representations
of them.
So if you were to do
this on the audio space,
you can think of some
similar analogies.
But long story cut short,
for a fairly well-performing
text-to-image system, these
are roughly the components
that you need.
So yeah.
And then let's now start
developing some notations so
that we can start discussing
about how these models are
trained.
And finally, how
you should perform
inference with these models.
So again, I'm giving this
examples with images.
But these are fairly agnostic--
modality agnostic, apart
from text.
Of course, this won't
work on discrete tokens.
So let's say I have
some original image
and I'm drawing some noise
from a standard Gaussian
distribution.
And then let's say I am
also drawing some time step
from a uniform distribution.
And then I have a particular
noise schedule and also
some terms that are
controlling the noise schedule.
And then let's say I have
some conditioning vector.
And by conditioning
vector I essentially mean
some text embeddings
or some other form
of structural control,
like let's say, depth map,
segmentation maps and so on.
And then you have your diffusion
model that you will learn.
And during training,
what we basically do
is we compute some intermediate
representations of the images.
Or let's say if you are
working on the pixel space,
you add small amount of
noise to your clean images
and you make the
model predict what
was the amount of
noise that was added.
This is one very popular
and widely adopted
parameterization of
diffusion network training.
It's called the epsilon
objective, if you will.
And that's basically it.
So we basically
make the model learn
what was the amount of
noise that was added.
So that's training.
And during sampling, we repeat
the noise prediction part
in a sequential manner, until
and unless we arrive at an image
that we feel good about.
So we start from a random
noise, and we denoise it
over a period of time with
some condition, which can be
text embeddings, for example.
And then we repeat the denoising
process over a period of time,
until and unless we
arrive at a data point
that we feel good about.
So yeah.
And for flow-matching which is
becoming more and more common
these days, for example, Flux.
If you have heard of the model
Flux or Stable Diffusion 3,
these are all
flow-matching-based.
In flow-matching, the
paths become more straight.
We try to connect
noise and clean data
through a straight path.
That's why you see the
linear interpolation
equation in the first point.
And we try to predict
the target velocity
field with a neural network.
So the key takeaway here is we
try to connect noise and clean
data through a straight line.
But in diffusion
models, the path
is not assumed to
be a straight line.
So that's why a lot
of simplification,
you will see in flow-matching.
But long story cut
short, in this talk,
we are more interested in the
network component of things.
We are not interested
in how you should
add the noise, what
particular noise schedules you
should follow, and so on.
We are more focused on
the parameterization
side of things in this talk.
So yeah.
And let's now start discussing
the components we might need,
the components that are
expected in a diffusion model.
What are the core
requirements that we
want to see in a
diffusion model to have
so that it performs within
some bound of expectations.
So we have to figure a way out
to deal with the noisy inputs.
As we saw, noise, we can't
really get rid of the noise
because that gives
us the foundation.
And usually in pixel
space your shapes
will look something like
this if your channels first.
And if you're working
on the latent space,
it will, of course,
be compressed a bit.
And we usually always deal
with the latent space diffusion
model.
So it helps to have
the shapes that you
would expect to see in your
models that will flow through.
And then you will have to
deal with the conditions
because all the text-to-image
models that you see,
text is your condition.
So you'll have to deal
with your conditions.
And of course time step.
So the amount of noise that
gets added to your latents,
it should depend
on the time step.
Let's say if your time step is
10, the amount of noise that
will get added to
your data points,
it will be different
from the time step--
if the time step were to be
somewhere like 1,000 or 100.
So that's why time step is
also a very crucial condition
because it basically
tells the model that
which point in the
trajectory it's in.
Should it denoise
less, should it denoise
more aggressively, and so on.
And then you have
got other forms
of conditions such as
class, maybe tiger, bird
or just like natural language.
And then we have to also model
the dependencies quite a bit.
How should the noisy inputs
interact with your conditions.
Of course, you might want
to think about these things
through the lens of
cross-attention and so on,
but we'll get to
that in a moment.
And then how should the
final outputs be produced?
Should we just flat
out decode everything
if we were to deal with
transformer-based architectures?
Should we be
upsampling if we were
to deal with pure convolutional
architectures, and so on?
And usually, for the
diffusion network,
the input shape exactly
equals the output shape,
until and unless you are dealing
with a separate parameterization
of diffusion.
There are other
parameterizations,
but it's way more common
to see the inputs that
are flowing through
the diffusion model
will equal the outputs
that the diffusion
model is supposed to produce.
And then, here's a
bit of a history.
So DDPM, all the early
work in this area--
DDPM latent diffusion
models, they all
used a UNet-based architectures.
And I think
historically speaking,
UNets have dominated this area
for quite a bit, like StyleGAN--
they all had a
UNet-based architecture.
And then until SDXL,
which is a fairly recent--
I would like to say recent
because it's from 2023.
And if you are trying to
develop a chronology of all
the architectures
that have come around,
I would like to argue that
SDXL is fairly decent.
And also based on its
usage, I think it's decent.
So until SDXL all the
works relied on UNet.
So I think it makes
sense to discuss
the UNet-based architecture
in this paradigm,
and then start seeing
why we really need
to transition to transformers.
So yeah.
And of course, the UNet
for diffusion, it's giant.
It's also one of the
reasons why you would
want to probably get rid of it.
But that's not the
end of the story.
But let's try to see what are
the different components that
are involved in our giant UNet.
So you of course, need to
have an input convolutional
stem that directly
operates at the inputs that
are coming at it.
And then you have a bunch of
downblocks, which is basically
comprised of custom
residual blocks made
of normalization layers
and convolutional layers.
And then you have got
custom transformer blocks.
Again, normalization projections
and regular transformer blocks.
And then you have got
convolutional layers
for upsampling.
So when you are operating
on the latent space,
you would want to upsample
to a higher resolution.
And then you would
have some middle block
like you would have in a
standard UNet architecture where
you would not have any
resolution changes.
And then you would have a series
of blocks which will basically
downsample the upsampled outputs
that you had in your downblocks.
And finally, you will
produce the output
that will have the same
shape as your input.
And it basically
resembles the same blocks
that you would have in
your downblock counterpart.
But instead of
doing upsampling, it
will have downsampling layers.
And there are some
miscellaneous things
that you should worry about,
for example, time step
embeddings-- how you should
embed your time steps,
and additional embeddings.
For example, if it's a
class conditional model,
the way to embed them
would be different.
If it's a tech like
text-to-image model,
the way to embed the text
embeddings would be different.
Basically, the way you modulate
all your conditional embeddings
that will change depending
on the kind of conditions
that you are dealing with.
And here's basically how
a downblock of the UNet
architecture looks like.
It's so, so giant that
I had to transpose it.
So it's very painful to
even think in the head.
So if you are someone that works
with architectures quite a bit,
I think we'll have to solemnly
agree that this is bad.
This is bad news already.
I can't even imagine
it in my head.
And here's a bit
of a zoomed in look
of what goes into that
downblock component of the UNet.
You have got a bunch
of custom ResNet blocks
as I was discussing.
I've got a bunch of
custom transformer blocks
as I was discussing,
but nothing too brutal.
Nothing that you
haven't seen already.
So it's just a bunch of
composition of those blocks.
And I have also tried mentioning
the resolution changes
in each of the stages.
And putting it all together,
it looks something like this.
I mean, I have tried
shortening it quite a bit,
but if I were to
imagine it in my head
it's going to be
extremely painful.
And the blocks are just--
damn.
It's very prohibitive
in nature just
for the task of
image generation.
So yeah.
That's the complete perspective.
I know it's not as complete
as you might expect,
but it's also hard to fit all
the UNet in a single screen.
So yeah.
And then of course,
the natural next thing
that one would
have tried would be
to try to replace the
convolutional layers with MLP
blocks, to try to
simplify quite a bit.
And yeah, folks
from Google tried it
in the UViT architecture.
So that's there.
That was the precursor to
the pure transformer-based
architectures, but not quite.
It still had its fair
share of complications,
and the architectural
painfulness as you
saw in the UNet-based design.
Now, I'm going to now try
to motivate why we really
need a pure transformer-based
architecture.
Now, the first point is
probably very obvious.
We would want to benefit
from the advancements that
are happening in the
transformer-based architectures,
like all the divine
benevolence, as Noam Shazeer
like likes to call it.
You would want to
have some gelu,
you would want to have
quick normalization,
parallel MLP layers and so on.
So that's one.
Of course, good scaling
properties ee and so on.
And then let's
say would you want
to connect the pure
transformer-based diffusion
architecture or the backbone,
with some other backbones,
let's say a pure
LLM-based backbone.
The integration
becomes very easy.
And then it allows
you to get rid
of the giant UNet, which I
guess is my main motivation.
But I hope I was able to
convince you fairly strongly why
we need a change--
a paradigm shift in the
architectures that are primarily
inspired from the UNet design.
And also, this is sight
to the sour eyes already.
This is not uncommon.
We all that this is
the standard forward
pass in a vision
transformer network.
They should feel very familiar
at this point in time.
Now, the point I am
trying to make here
is this doesn't have to
change a whole lot if we
were to extrapolate this
to image generation.
And I think you will agree
with me that this is not
changing a lot.
All the core
components are there,
the patchification is there, the
positional embeddings are there.
Of course, the way to
class embed things, that's
different-- the y embedder bit.
You would still need
to have a component
to embed your time steps--
that's different.
But the rest of the
components is still there.
You are still iterating
through the blocks.
You have your final
layer to finally decode
your outputs and so on, and
the non-patchification layer.
So this is still very similar
to how you would do it
in a standard width.
But of course, you have to you
account for the generation head
also at the same time.
So my point is you
are not changing
a whole lot in the standard
width forward pass.
Now, taking a
closer look, I think
this should also feel very
familiar, apart from a few mods
here and there.
We have got some scale and
shift parameters, which
I'm going to discuss in a bit.
But the rest of
the other blocks,
you have got the same layer now,
you have got the patchification
layer, you have
got some embeddings
and so on, and then you have got
a linear and reshape operation.
So most of it should
feel familiar.
But the ones that are
apparently a little foreign,
I'm going to discuss them now.
Let's start with
the time step bit.
How do we actually
embed time steps?
I've been talking about time
steps for quite a bit now.
But let's now see how do we
actually embed the time steps.
And time steps are
really important.
And I'm also going to show
you the expected shapes,
the output shapes.
And in this case,
this is batch size,
comma, the hidden dimension
of the transformer
blocks that you are expecting.
So how do we embed time steps?
And time steps can range
in between 0 to 1,000,
where 0 meaning like no noise,
and 1,000 should mean it's fully
noised.
So each t is embedded
into sinusoidal frequency
to make them phase aware.
At any point in
time, the network
is seeing extremely low
frequencies and extremely high
frequencies.
And it must be aware
of the kind of phase
it should be modulating into.
So that's why sinusoidal
frequencies are really helpful.
And then after that, how
the network should weigh
these different frequencies.
And in order to
model those weights,
we basically pass it
through a very shallow MLP.
And then how do you
embed class labels?
You just take an
nn.Embedding layer--
as simple as that.
And this is the standard
patchification--
you do it with a
convolutional stem.
And for positional
encodings they
use the standard
sine-cosine scheme.
And the final conditioning is
you first embed the time steps
and then you embed
the class labels,
and you basically sum them up.
And then you have
your final condition
that goes into the
transformer blocks.
And this is very important
to note that c remains
fixed across all the blocks.
So that's very
important to note.
And you would probably
think the conditioning--
in order to model
the conditioning
with the actual inputs,
the noisy latency
would probably want to
use cross-attention,
but that's not the case, as we
will see in a few slides later.
So let's take a
step back and try
to think of how we can
inject the conditioning bit
into the transformer blocks.
So we have something called
adaptive layer-norm, which
is very important in
order to be able to model
the stylistic aspects that you
are getting out of your images.
And it's basically this--
so you have your
standard layer norm,
and then you have
an additional set
of parameters which we call
modulation parameters, which
basically operate on
the condition space.
And remember, the
condition is basically
a summation of the
time step embeddings,
as well as the class embeddings.
So that's your
condition right there.
And skipping the regular
transformer bits like the QKV,
the multi-head, self-attention
and the MLP layers--
we the equations that
govern the computations
that take place within a
standard transformer encoder
block.
So this is fairly well-known.
And the part that's not
known at this point in time
hopefully is how do we
modulate the conditioning bit.
How do we actually inject the
conditioning in the transformer
blocks?
So this is how we do it.
Instead of doing
any cross-attention
which would have been a fairly
natural choice, I guess.
We actually do not
do cross-attention.
We are still doing
self-attention,
and then we are basically
modulating the conditioning
along with
self-attention, as you
can see in the bottom
half of your equations.
And these modulation parameters
are learned from the modality
that you are training
these things on.
And then in order to
get your final outputs,
you basically have a
single layer decoder.
And then you
basically unpatchify
it to get the same
shape as your inputs.
Now, a note on init,
because the initialization
is fairly important-- it's all
standard vision transformer,
init, but with two
key modifications.
Each transformer block is
initialized as identity block,
taking inspiration from
the early works in ImageNet
training, wherein if you have
a bunch of ResNet blocks,
you usually initialize the
beta parameter in the batch
normalization layer as 0.
It helps with training
stability, and stabilization.
And it turns out that's
the case here as well.
Now, coming to the adaptive
layer normalization thing.
It's very important and it's
also more compute efficient.
And as I was mentioning,
cross-attention
would have been the
natural choice in order
to model the dependency between
the conditions and the noise
inputs.
But that's not at all the case
if you take a look at the graph.
In fact, adaptive layer-norm
performs the best,
and it beats
cross-attention big time.
And it's also not because
the conditions are fairly
simple to model, but it's
because when you are operating
with continuous
modalities like images,
it's not that trivial
to model dependencies
with cross-attention.
And when your conditions are
simple like class embeddings,
it doesn't make sense to model
them with cross-attention.
It's also because it's
a waste of compute,
and the graph confirms it.
And later works
have also explored
a more compute efficient variant
of adaptive layer-norm, which
we are going to get to
in a couple slides later.
And how you are modulating
these conditions--
in this case, we are
basically operating
on a summation of the time
step embeddings and the class
embeddings.
Now, how you are modulating
it across and throughout
your different
transformer blocks,
that becomes very
important, as we will see
in a couple of blocks later.
And as expected, it
scales fairly graciously
with more compute.
And it turns out that
you can basically
apply all the UNet-based
training techniques
to a diffusion transformer.
So that's pretty cool.
It scales pretty graciously.
Performs also well
when compared to other
equally sized unit counterparts.
And of course, at
this point in time,
you must be thinking
no one really
does class conditional in the
space of image generation.
So yeah, that's where
we are headed next.
Now, I want to try
to motivate what
it would take to enable
text-to-image generation
in the standard diffusion
transformer architecture,
because I think it
makes sense to approach
the problem in that sense.
What are the components that are
missing in a standard diffusion
transformer, so that
it becomes a tool
for text-to-image
generation as well?
And I think PixArt-alpha is
one of the early works that
explored it.
So yeah, we are going to
definitely see it in details.
Now, one natural
question would be
how to embed the input
natural language text prompts.
And the answer would be simple.
You will need a text encoder.
And that's exactly what
the PixArt-alpha work does.
And then how to learn your
contextual dependencies.
Now we have instead of
class instead of classes,
we have got natural language
text on top of time steps.
We could do self-attention
on noisy latents,
and then we could
do cross-attention
in between your noisy
latents and text.
And mind you, this
text is not just class.
This text is some natural
language description,
like a baby astronaut hatching
out of an egg on the moon.
So this is natural
language description
we are talking about.
This is not simply class labels.
So that could make sense.
It could make sense to have
self-attention on noisy latents
to model the local dependencies
within the patches,
and then also do cross-attention
in between the noisy patches
and the text embeddings.
And then we'll have
to figure a way out
to modulate the
time steps as well.
And as we saw in the
DiT work that it's
important to modulate
the time step
embeddings throughout
your transformer blocks.
And then if you have got access
to a class conditional diffusion
transformer, and
if it's compatible,
it might also make sense to
initialize some blocks from it.
Because why waste compute?
It might help with training
stabilization and so on.
Now, that's exactly
what PixArt-alpha does.
So if you were paying attention
at this point in time,
you would have realized that
implementing these things
is not extremely challenging.
But it helps to know that that's
exactly what PixArt-alpha does.
So it uses a text encoder
to embed the prompts.
It uses self-attention
on noisy latents.
It uses cross-attention
to model the dependency
between the noisy latents
and the text embeddings.
And it also initializes from
a class conditional DiT model
in order to accelerate training.
So it helps to that you can
still think about these things
and see it getting
implemented in practice.
And here's some discussion
around the use of text encoder.
So PixArt-alpha used
Flan-T5-xxl in order
to really get that
text-rendering ability.
And some of the concurrent
works like Imagine,
they showed that if you
scale the text encoder,
and if you ever wanted to
render text in your images,
having a better text
encoder actually helps.
And also, then
there's this problem
of long prompt
following ability,
because models like SDXL, they
rely on clip for embedding text.
And CLIP has a very
short context length.
I think it's 77.
But with the T5-xxl, you get
a way longer context length.
So you basically get
to have longer prompts.
You get to describe your
prompt in a bit more detail.
So that's there.
And also exploring the
space of text encoder,
it's still a good research
problem to take a look at.
And if you were
wondering, why not
just use a standard language
model in place of T5?
Well, it's not that
difficult to actually use it.
At many works like Lumina,
they explore it quite a bit.
And if you were wondering,
diffusion models
are already compute bound.
So why add the baggage of
adding another heavy model?
Well, I think it's OK to
use that because computing
prompt embedding it's
a one step process.
So it's OK to have
a memory bound model
like a large language
model in the mix.
Cool.
And here, we will again see the
return of adaptive layer-norm.
And remember if you
forgot, remember
that for each diffusion
transformer block,
we were operating on a summation
of time step embeddings
and class embeddings.
For PixArt-alpha, we
already have a way
to compute our text embeddings,
which we do not want to touch,
because those
embeddings are already
computed with a dedicated
rich text encoder.
So we maybe do not want
to touch those embeddings
and modulate them.
Unlike diffusion transformers,
where we modulated
the class embeddings as well.
And instead of having
adaptive layer normalization
blocks in every diffusion
transformer encoder block,
we basically maintain tables.
We basically maintain embedding
tables and we sum them up.
So instead of doing
another matmul
for each and every
transformer encoder block,
we basically get
away with addition.
Addition with another
embedding table.
And it helps us reduce
the compute quite a bit.
It helps us reduce 27% of the
original diffusion transformer
computation.
And I think the idea
is fairly elegant.
It also gives
another perspective
to think about how you can
reduce parameters and still
maintain performance.
So this was good.
Cool.
And I must say this is
impressive performance
for a fairly compact model.
It's only 0.6 billion
parameter model.
And it's already
breaking all the charts.
When it came around in
2023, it was fairly good.
I think I have the
[? Geneva ?] scores.
No, we don't.
But the last chart
here, it basically
shows you the human
preference rating.
Quality wise, it's
overall image quality.
And alignment wise,
it's the alignment
between the text and
the generated images.
And in both of those
aspects, PixArt-alpha
performed fairly well.
Now, before I jump to the time
and memory complexity of these
models-- because we are still
using the quadratic vanilla
attention thing--
I want to see if there are any
questions at this point in time.
So I'm going to open the floor
for questions if that's OK,
Stephen?
That's OK.
Yeah.
Go ahead.
You mentioned that the state
of the art diffusion models
rely on more than
one text encoder.
Why is that?
Or what's the benefit of
having multiple different types
of encodings for the same text?
Oh yeah.
For sure.
So the question
is, why would you
want to have multiple
text encoders,
and why does it help improve the
image generation performance?
So you saw in class
conditional DiTs,
you modulate not just
the time step embeddings,
but also the class embeddings.
So the conditional embeddings
that we were modulating, along
with self-attention were a
summation of class embeddings
and time step embeddings.
Now, for text-to-image models,
that is not as trivial.
So apart from your
text embeddings,
you also have your
time step embeddings.
But what about modulating
the other condition that you
computed from your text input?
So turns out that the richer
the representations are,
the diverse the
representations are,
the better it is for
the generation backbone.
Now, when I said many models do
use more than one text encoders,
they usually have a
combination of CLIP and T5.
Now CLIP is an entirely
different model
and T5 is an entirely
different model.
With CLIP, you embed some
kind of contrastive nature
in the text embeddings,
and with T5 you
have a completely different
nature in your text embeddings.
So the more the diverse
are these embeddings,
the better it is for the
generative performance.
But there is no
systematic study of this.
That's what the
general belief is.
Yeah.
But there are works that
get away just by using
a single language model.
Maybe the language models
inherit both as a virtue
of their good pre-training.
Yeah.
Any more questions?
Do most current
cutting-edge companies
use diffusion transformers
now, or are some still using
the original UNet
with convolutions,
or is it just dependent
on the use case?
I think most of them are using
diffusion transformers because
of their efficiencies, and
also they are easy to adapt.
If you wanted to embed
another form of control--
let's say you wanted
to additionally prompt
the model with some stylistic
reference from images,
it's easier to do that on
a diffusion transformer,
as you would, as we will see
in a couple of slides later.
How do you exactly avoid
the matrix multiplication?
Oh yeah.
Sure.
Can you expand a little bit?
Yeah, sure.
In the original diffusion
transformer block,
you initialize all your
modulation parameters
as basically an affine layer.
So you can do that.
You can chunk it and then you
have your different modulation
parameters.
And this is where your
matrix multiplication lies.
And notice how I am computing
the modulation parameters.
But here I am only computing
it through an embedding table.
There's no affine
transformation happening.
And I end up adding it to
my time step embeddings.
That's it.
So that's how I
avoid the matmul.
And that's largely why
I am able to reduce
the computation by 27%.
I'll take one last
question before I
jump to the next
section, if there's any.
Some over Zoom,
as well as online.
I'll ask some.
Let me see.
Someone's wondering is there
still any point of GANs
for image and video
generation, or have they
been fully replaced basically
with diffusion models?
I won't say they have been fully
replaced, because as we saw,
diffusion models are still
sequential in nature.
So if you are looking for really
ultra real-time generation,
I think GANs are
still the way to go,
and many companies are
in fact using them.
So if you're looking for really
cool one-shot generation,
I think GANs is the way.
So there's this literature
around time step distillation
that basically looks at reducing
the number of time steps
or inference steps that you
need in order to produce
a good quality image.
There you need a
GAN loss actually.
So GANs are not going to
be completely replaced yet.
Because I thought GANs had a lot
of issues like mode collapse--
Oh yeah, they have.
But if you have got
specific use cases
and if you have got a
fairly good data set,
you can still train a good GAN.
I can ask one more
this time from online.
Image generation generally
requires a lot of data
to train, especially
for diffusion models.
Are there techniques or
architectural choices
for low data regimes?
That's a good one.
Short answer is no.
I think it's kind of correlated
with your use case a bit.
For medical imaging,
probably you
do not need a whole
lot of diversity.
But if you need a fairly well
and generic generative model,
I think you need to
train it on a lot of data
to inherit all the biases
that you are looking for.
If you want to train on the
distribution of natural images
and you want the model to
always produce realistic images,
I think you need to
have a lot of data--
at least a diverse data.
Because nowadays for
LLMs, there's zero-shot,
few-shot learning
after you pre-trained--
I'm going to talk a bit
about in-context learning
for diffusion models.
But you are assuming you have
access to a pre-trained model.
So there you go.
All right.
I'm going to start
this leg of the talk
by discussing the quadratic
time and memory complexity
argument a bit., because now
we are in the image generation
territory.
And when you are trying to
generate really high resolution
images, like 4K images, vanilla
attention becomes extremely
prohibitive, even if you were
to operate on the latent space.
Take a look at the
dimensions of the latents.
Let's say your number of
latent channels is 16,
and your latent
dimensions are 512, 512.
It's still way too large--
way larger than what we are
used to seeing in the VLM space.
And I have some dummy
computations here.
This is, of course, not
using flash attention.
If I were to give you
some dummy estimates,
it would be like 190 GBs
in floating-point 16.
And this is all like
reasonable defaults.
I have 24 attention heads.
I've got batch size one.
The sequence length
is flattened out.
I would need 190 GB.
And this is, of course,
not using flash attention.
But you get an idea of the
prohibitive computation space
of the quadratic
attention that we usually
use in diffusion
models if we were
to deal with really high quality
and high resolution images.
So what could we do?
Two simple things
that we could do
is operate on an even
more compressed space,
like this-- this
1, 16, 512, 512.
This space is already
compressed enough.
But could we even increase
the compression ratio further?
And then the second
obvious thing
could be to use some
form of linear attention
that doesn't do the n
cross in multiplication.
So that brings me to
my next architecture,
which is the SANA architecture.
And it uses both.
It uses an even more
compressed latent space,
and it also uses
a linear variant
of the attention mechanism.
So let's see.
So our linear attention
is on the other hand.
And of course, you might
expect some performance loss
with the linear complexity
of the attention mechanism.
And to compensate
for the performance
lost, we use Mix-FFN.
And I'm going to get into
the details in a bit.
But just wanted to give
you a quick overview.
So SANA does self-attention--
self linear attention,
as you will.
But it still does
cross attention
to model the dependencies
between the noisy latents,
as well as the text prompts
that you are providing it too.
And then there's no
n square computation
happening in the
self-attention, and the equation
makes that clear.
So we have got shared
terms, shared terms computed
from the kV projections.
And these are reused
for all the queries.
And this way, we are
basically and effectively not
doing the n cross
in multiplications.
And all of the multiplications
are upper bound to n.
So that's why we are
able to reduce from order
of mn squared to order of n.
And then, as I was
mentioning, there
has to be some form
of accountability
as we are not using the
quadratic attention mechanism.
So we use Mix-FFN blocks.
It's basically a bunch of
inverted residual blocks
and pointwise
convolutions in order
to model the local dependencies.
Because it turns
out that when you
take the softmax
out of the picture,
you lose all the
notion of locality.
Let's not say all--
majority of the locality
notions are taken out also.
So that's why you need some
components to also model
the locality aspect.
And Mix-FFN blocks
are used for that.
And for the first time SANA got
rid of the positional embedding
bit.
So it's very funny to say it--
NoPe.
So no positional embeddings.
And mixed blocks actually
helps because you
have a bunch of convolutional
blocks in there.
So we are still returning to
the convolutional argument,
but not so much.
It's not fully convolutional.
You just have a few
convolutional layers
thrown in there.
So it's largely DiT-based.
But instead of
using a linear MLP,
you have two
convolutional layers
to account for the
local interactions.
And it performs really well.
For its compact size,
it performs fairly well.
I must say that we shouldn't
take into account the kernel
fusion and the fancy DPM
solver that they're using.
But up until the fourth
row, I think it's still
performing fairly well.
It's giving very decent
general performance.
It's giving very
decent DPG performance.
And these are all metrics that
assess a given image in terms
of compositionality, in
terms of their fidelity,
in terms of their overall
quality, and so on.
And these metrics are fairly
well-grounded in terms
of reality.
And this is probably going to
be the final flavor of attention
that I'm going to discuss before
I move on to other topics.
And this is, I think, a bit new.
And also new in the sense
that no one in the VLM space
really does it.
So what happens if
we were to model
dependencies of the different
modalities in separate spaces?
So let's see.
And one motivation behind
this could be text embeddings.
Let's say you are computing text
embeddings with a large language
model.
You will end up inheriting
a lot of bias from it.
The unidirectionality
bias will be there.
If you are using a standard
autoregressive large language
model, you will
end up inheriting
the unidirectionality bias.
So you will have
bias, and they might
creep into your generative model
in all sorts of different ways.
So one idea could be to do QKV
projections but separately.
You do QKV projections
on the text embeddings,
and you also maintain another
set of QKV projection parameters
for your noisy latents.
And then you concatenate
them before you
compute the attention.
So you operate on a
concatenated representation
before you actually
do the attention.
And conceptually, this
becomes basically this.
So you project your QKV
stuff on your image latents
separately from the
text embeddings.
You concatenate them before
you actually compute attention.
So this is basically it.
So this is MMDiT that was
introduced in the Stable
Diffusion 3 paper.
And their motivation
was to get rid
of the different biases
that might be there
in the text embeddings.
And they also showed how
qualitatively different text
embeddings can be from
the image embeddings.
So I guess that
kind of gives you
a hint about why we might need
different text embeddings,
to not end up inheriting
each other's biases
and have more
diversity in the mix.
So it basically looks like this.
So it might feel a
little complicated.
But the reason
why it's so big is
because we have
separate projection
matrices for the different
modalities that we are modeling.
So on the left-hand side,
we have got the captions.
And on the right-hand side,
we have got the noisy latents.
And we have got
separate QKV projections
and adaptive layer-norm matrices
for the separate modalities.
So that's why it feels big.
But conceptually
it's basically this.
So you have got separate
adaptive layer-norm matrices
for the separate modalities.
You have got separate
QKV projection matrices.
output projection matrices.
And then you have got
separate-- everything separate.
Everything is separate
from the two modalities
that we are interested in.
So in a way, it gives a way
to coevolve the two embeddings
from the two
different modalities
that we are working with
for the given task, which is
image generation in this case.
And also, if we are very
used to cross-attention,
you might want to ask if we
were to compute attention
in this way, how do we do
masking in the first place?
And that's actually an
active area of research.
We do not how to do
masks holistically,
if we were to do a MMDiT
variant of attention.
And then, modulation
happens with both time steps
and the conditional embedding
that you are operating with.
So Stable Diffusion 3 uses a
different set of pooled text
embeddings that are usually
computed from CLIP, and not
the T5-based text encoder.
So again, you need
some form of diversity
to not end up inheriting the
bias from the other text encoder
that you had.
And Stable Diffusion
3 uses three,
but they can be mixed and
matched during inference.
They showed that you
need the T5 if you
need to have really good
text rendering capabilities.
But other than
that, you can still
do a lot with the two
clips that they use.
And you can drop the T5 if
you are not solely focused
on text rendering tasks.
And of course, it
matters quite a bit.
You might want to ask,
does MMDiT matter at all?
And it turns out
that it does matter.
They tried all forms of
different attention variants.
They tried crossDiT,
they tried UViT,
and MMDiT seems to be the
variant that gives you
the lowest validation loss.
And they also show that
validation loss is fairly well
correlated with the
kind of image generation
metrics that we care about,
such as [? Geneva ?] and so on.
And it scales fairly well,
but it needs QK-normalization.
And thanks to the
concurrent set of works,
they didn't have to reinvent
QK-norm from the scratch.
So thanks to developments in the
regular transformer literature,
they were able to just use
QK-norm to solve the training
instability issues.
And I think Stable
Diffusion 3 is
basically incomplete
without this picture.
And I'm not showing this
picture just for fun,
but also because it shows
how complex is this prompt,
and how well Stable
Diffusion 3 was
able to interpret this prompt
and get us a creature like this.
So I must give credits to the
authors of Stable Diffusion
3 who came up with
these kinds of prompts,
but it does fairly well.
So it was among the
first kinds of models
that shows impressive
prompt following ability,
and also while also preserving
the details that we care about.
So that was cool.
And MMDiT didn't stop here.
There are different flavors of
MMDiT that I wanted to discuss.
In Stable Diffusion 3,
all the transformer blocks
followed the MMDiT
flavor of attention,
and it's computationally
demanding.
If you have worked with
transformer encoders,
you would appreciate
the computation
and the computational
intensity of MMDiTs,
because you are having to
maintain separate projection
matrices for the
different modalities
that you are working with.
So it's computationally
extremely demanding.
So maybe we could combine MMDiT
blocks and regular DiT blocks
to be able to better
utilize the flops.
So conceptually
this becomes this.
So you have some number
of memory blocks.
You concatenate the
final representation
and then you operate on
the concatenate space
and basically do vanilla it.
You do not do MMDiT
and you end up
utilizing the flops
a little better.
And that's exactly what recent
models like Flux from Black
Forest labs, they do.
So another twisty one could
be you have modality A,
you compute output
A by passing it
through a bunch of
transformer blocks.
And then you have got modality
B, let's say text embeddings.
You pass it through another
set of transformer blocks.
You concatenate these
outputs, and then you
pass them through another
set of transformer blocks.
And then you basically
have your final output.
And in this way,
you can configure
all the different blocks
in their own manner.
The transformer
blocks for modality A
could be different from
the transformer blocks
that you would use for
modality B. So this way
you have a greater level
of flexibility and control.
And that's what the
Lumina2 work did.
And as we can see,
for conditions,
they pass it through a separate
set of transformer blocks.
For noisy latents, they pass
it through a separate set
of transformer blocks.
And they end up
concatenating them,
and then again they have another
set of transformer blocks.
So transformer blocks on the
left-hand side in the RHS
big block can be different from
the transformer blocks used
to model the noisy latents.
So you have got greater
flexibility and control.
And I want to give
you a sense of how
we can think of simplifying
all of this design,
because it might
feel complicated
at this point in time.
But I don't know, maybe we
can simplify it quite a bit.
But I want to quickly
see if there are
any questions at this point.
Do you have any
questions over Zoom?
Yeah, we got some
online questions.
Let me see.
Somebody just asked, is GPT
4 a completely different
architecture?
How does that compare with
the diffusion transformer?
That's a good one.
I think it uses a
hybrid architecture.
It definitely has an LLM
component to it, which
was evolved to generate images.
I'm going to come to this hybrid
architectures in a moment.
And then someone's
wondering, for evaluation,
are there good automatic metrics
for image and video generation,
or is it mainly human-based
subjective evaluation
similar to creative writing?
I think it's an ensemble
of different metrics.
You can't evaluate an
image on a single metric.
And also, it depends on what
you are exactly looking for.
If you are more interested
in compositionality,
the metrics will change.
If you are more
interested in aesthetics,
the metrics will change.
So that depends.
Let me see.
What are your thoughts
on diffusion models--
Someone noted that there's
a common perspective
about image generation models
failing to generate things
like fingers.
I also see that on
Reddit posts and stuff.
Do they still suffer from
things like counting and spatial
consistency, or are those basic
things pretty much solved?
I think models like
flags definitely,
they do a whole lot better.
And there's a question.
What are the major
additional challenges
of video generation compared
to image generation,
and ways to overcome them?
Well, the first
problem is the time,
because diffusion-based image
generation models are already
compute intensive.
And then with video
generation models,
you have got another
dimension of temporality.
So they just become
more compute intensive.
And then you have got more
curse of dimensionality
to basically address.
And then if you are generating
more and more frames,
they just become more and
more compute intensive.
So how do you make them
more efficient is definitely
the need of the hour.
It also adds things like
temporal dependencies.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah.
Another axis of
dependency to model.
And you are basically
doing full 3D attention,
which is extremely prohibitive
to even think about.
[INAUDIBLE] just have to treat
it like you wouldn't have to--
I'm sorry.
I didn't get the question.
In the video, you don't
have to generate frame
by frame from scratch.
You already have something more
or less figured out, and then
just do a small change.
If you take a 2D image
generation model and if you try
to conflate it such that it
can also do spatial-temporal
generation, well,
it doesn't turn out.
It will work well, at least
in the realistic setting.
If you wanted to generate
cinematic frames,
it won't work because the
spatial-temporal consistency,
it just gets lost.
[INAUDIBLE]
But there has to be a limit.
If you are operating
with that many frames
as your previous
input, the queue also
becomes extremely prohibitive.
So you have to
figure out how you
can compress the temporal
dimension effectively.
Let's say you have a
variable number of frames.
Now, how do you map it on
the latent temporal level
so that it still has some
meaning to it, while being
efficient at the same time?
So when you are doing
videos, you no longer just
have the spatial
compression, but also you
have temporal compression.
And how do you model the
two as you make progress?
Are there any other questions?
I'll just take one maybe.
Someone on Zoom's
asked, can you give
some intuition about
adaptive layer normalization
and why it works so well?
Oh yeah.
So for layer-norm,
you are basically
using layer-norm for stabilizing
training, I would say.
You have more stable
representations
across the blocks.
But for images, there
are certain kind
of characteristics
that you would
want to model beyond the
standard representations
that you are computing.
And you will have to let
those features flow freely
into your transformer blocks.
And that's why you need
the modulation parameters.
Otherwise the interaction
in between the normalization
parameters and your
regular attention
features or whatever MLP
features that you are computing,
they don't get to interact
in a way that will benefit
the generation performance.
If you were to deal with just
understanding or maybe just
discriminative
performance, it wouldn't
have mattered that much.
But if you care about
stylistic aspects and fidelity,
you need to modulate the
additional features that you are
getting from the visual cues.
Yeah.
Any other questions?
It's like a mission.
We don't know yet how
[INAUDIBLE] masking--
For MMDiT.
Yeah.
[INAUDIBLE] What's
the next best thing?
Is there an
alternative to masking?
Maybe that's a hunch.
Why would you need masking.
That's a good question
to ask for MMDiT.
So MMDiT was done in
order to benefit--
in order to get away with
the unidirectionality bias
that you may have in your text
embedding representations.
So that was one.
Second, if you have
really long prompts,
you do not need to compute
masks in the first place.
And it also turns out
that it's always better
to have long prompts,
like descriptive prompts,
rather than having to
have short prompts.
So that is kind of a hand-wavy
way to answer this question.
But long story cut short, it's
really non-trivial to add masks
when you are doing
MMDiT attention.
So there you go.
[OVERLAPPING VOICES] was about
doing separately QKV on both
text--
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
How about on the image side?
So when you are doing
the image interaction
you could in theory do masks.
But again, how would
you frame the problem?
Where would you end
up adding the masks?
If you are just doing
text to image, maybe.
Maybe if you have another
form of conditional control,
maybe you would want to mask
some of the interactions there.
But if you are just
restricted to text-to-image,
where would you add the
masks in the first place?
What I'm asking is
to avoid masking.
Oh.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Probably that's why they didn't
do masking in the first place.
Maybe their motivations--
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Exactly, exactly.
I'll maybe take one final
question if there's any.
OK, cool.
So I also want to leave
you with some ideas
for simplifying
the design a bit.
If these things felt a little
complicated, because they do not
have to be complicated at all.
We can simplify it quite
a bit, and let's see how.
So how much is parameter
shading is useful?
Things like adaLN that we saw
and the work on PixArt-alpha
that reduce the
computation by 27%.
How much is that kind of
parameter shading is useful?
And we saw adaLN already.
Can we also share QKVO
and the MLP, like Albert?
This is from back in the days--
Albert where we shared
all the projection
matrices for a couple of layers.
We also shared the MLP
matrices and so on.
And do we really
need self-attention
and then cross-attention,
or do we really need MMDiT?
I think this will probably
answer your question,
so I look forward to that.
So do we really
need these things?
Because this, in a sense,
complicates the design space
quite a bit.
Can we simplify it?
So can we basically
do self-attention
on this concatenated space?
We do not have to do
self-attention on noisy latents.
We do not have to
do cross-attention
on noisy latents and text.
We do not have to do MMDiT.
Can we basically concatenate all
the image tokens and the text
tokens and compute
self-attention on it?
Can we do it?
And text encoders,
what's the secret sauce?
We are using three,
we are using two--
what helps?
What helps the cause of
text-to-image generation
at the end of the day?
It turns out you can
simplify things a lot.
So one thing that you can do
is you can parameter share
quite a bit.
You can parameter share QKVO if
you are looking for efficiency.
You can definitely
parameter share
the adaptive
layer-norm parameters.
And you can basically
do self-attention
on a concatenated representation
space of image tokens and text
tokens.
So this is, I think, good news,
but not so much because Apple
didn't open source this work.
So we'll have to do our own.
But this is good to that you can
simplify the design quite a bit.
So the extreme right-hand
side is the simplified design
that I was talking about.
So you are basically operating
on a concatenated space.
You are reducing the adaptive
layer-norm parameters
quite a bit.
And then you are parameter
sharing the QKV projections
as well as the MLP layers.
And it turns out to be working
well-- fairly well, I must say,
in practice.
So the green one is
the simplified design,
and it always gets the
lowest amount of loss.
So yeah.
And as I was mentioning,
other than sharing
the adaptive
layer-norm parameters,
you can also share the QKV
parameters as well as the MLP,
if you can compromise
some of the quality a bit,
and if you are only
targeting efficiency.
And for text encoders,
the Apple folks
found out that bidirectional
CLIP and text only LLM
is better.
So instead of using a
combination of CLIP and T5,
if you use CLIP and a
regular large language model,
it's better for text
representations.
So the performance
is pretty good.
The final row is Apple's work.
It's called DiT-Air.
So turns out fairly well.
All the bold numbers from DiT.
So it turns out pretty well.
So long story cut short, you can
simplify the design quite a bit.
So you do not need
MMDiT as it turns out.
But we will see, I guess.
Now, one burning question you
must be having at this point
in time is, text-to-image
is liberating,
but how do I inject
more control--
more sources of control?
If I were to do more
structural inputs
to my text-to-image
model, how do I do that?
Maybe I want the model to
follow a particular pose.
follow a particular segmentation
map and so on.
And how do I do that?
And can I combine multiple
structural signals
at the same time?
So one could be to learn maybe
an auxiliary network that
gives you a way to compute
salient representations
from your structural
image signals.
And maybe you then
figure a way out
to inject those structural
signals into your base diffusion
model.
So that could be one.
And ControlNet, these lines
of work, they basically
follow this philosophy.
And then maybe you could also
change the base diffusion
transformer model.
You basically increase
your input channels
to accept more controls.
And that's what the
FluxControl framework does.
And maybe you could also
learn a small adapter network
to model the dependencies
between all your conditions
and your noisy latent tokens.
And also one important
call out here
is structural
control will always
have spatial correspondence,
but other tasks
like subject-driven
generation or image edits,
they may not have direct
spatial correspondence.
So what do we do in those cases?
And this is, again, an
active area of research.
And for videos, well,
RoPE works fairly well
for positional encoding.
And as I was mentioning, the
attention computation space
becomes way more prohibitive
because it's full 3D.
And if you were
thinking about some form
of factorized attention,
it doesn't work.
I have been very
explicit about it.
And for efficiency, if
you are particularly
interested in efficiency-related
literature around video models,
I highly suggest checking
out the LTX-Video work.
And for performance,
like for fidelity,
photorealism, and so on, I
think Wan has to be my favorite.
It's pretty good.
I have a little demo here.
It's not that bad.
So it's still short form
video, but the realism aspect
and the fidelity
aspect of these videos,
I think they have
improved quite a bit.
And some next generation
architectures.
Now I'm coming towards
the end of my talk.
I wanted to also
give you a flavor
and a sense of next
generation architectures.
You probably have
this question, how
do we enable in-context
learning in diffusion models?
In language model, it's
very common-- zero-shot
learning and so on.
How do we enable in-context
learning in diffusion models?
Current architectures
are clearly not
sufficient to enable it
in a reasonable time.
So the basic idea is
you take an LLM model,
you add some components
so that it also
becomes adept at
generating images
like recent works like Bagel.
Then there are works
like [INAUDIBLE]--
they basically follow
this area of work.
They are not necessarily
diffusion-based,
but they share a
similar philosophy.
So you basically start
from a pre-trained LLM,
you add components to it
so that it also becomes
adept at generating images.
You could do autoregression on
discrete tokens, for example.
And you could also do, at
the same time diffusion,
on the continuous tokens.
So that's one line of work
that's called transfusion.
So as I was mentioning, there's
Playground v3, there's FuseDiT,
there'ss Transfusion.
FuseDiT is from our group.
It's the only open source
work that you will probably
find that tackles this problem
of in-context learning,
and how do you explore
these architectures
in a holistic manner.
And if you are already
feeling inspired--
I hope you are feeling inspired
to explore these architectures.
I highly welcome you to
check out the library
that I work on at Hugging Face.
It's called diffusers.
We have got reasonably
clean implementations
of all the models that
I discussed today,
which should probably inspire
you to hack into these things
and tweak them.
And there's a bunch of things
I didn't get to cover, of .
I am a little bit over time.
I think one minute over time.
I'm probably going to finish
it in the next one minute,
so I apologize.
I didn't cover MoEs.
Hot topic again.
But MoEs are making their ways
in the diffusion community.
It's called HiDream.
I didn't cover training at all.
There are all kinds
of shenanigans there.
How do you do data?
How do you do alignment?
How do you do post-training?
How do you do safety mitigation?
How do you do memorization,
mitigation, and so on?
And of course,
these architectures
go well beyond image
and video generation.
They find their application
in all sorts of stuff
like robotics, gene
synthesis, and so on.
And if you are into
mechanistic interpretability,
interpretation of these
beasts are not trivial at all.
So they interest me quite well.
And yeah, that's about it.
Thank you.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDING]